# **Dustin Irving**

## Full Stack Web Developer

Email: dustin.irving@gmail.com Phone: +1 613-292-4533 Location: Ottawa. ON

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dustin-

irving-a92009194/

GitHub: https://github.com/dustinirving

Portfolio: https://dustinirving.github.io/portfolio

## **SKILLS**

Client HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap,

JavaScript (ES6+),

Jquery.js, React.js

ServerNode.js, ExpressDatabaseMySQL, MongoDB

**Other** Express Handlebars, EJS,

ORMs, JSON, Git/ Github

**RESTful APIs** 

## **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web Developer with a certificate in Web Development via Carleton University's Coding Bootcamp and a Bachelor of Science with a Specialization in Biochemistry from the University of Ottawa. Exceptional problem solving skills, able to thrive in a team environment and a strong desire to learn. Technical abilities include: creating responsive and interactive user interfaces, using RESTful APIs, setting up servers, retrieving data from SQL and NoSQL databases and many more.

### **PROJECTS**

Travelbook Live Site Github Repo

Travelbook is a full-stack application which allows users to create an account and post about their travel experiences. Some other features include: editing and deleting posts, updating your profile, and connecting with nearby travellers. This project was developed with semantic UI, EJS, Node.js, Express, Sequelize and MySQL.

COVID-19 Tracker Live Site Github Repo

The COVID-19 Tracker retrieves the latest data regarding cases of COVID-19 and displays a graphical representation. It also provides the user with the most recent news updates. This was all done with MaterializeCSS, HTML5, JavaScript, Chart.js, an open source COVID-19 API, and the New York Times API.

### **Employee Tracking CLI**

Github Repo

This is a command line tool that allows the user to track employees regarding their role, department and manager. The user can select from a variety of options to update information in the database. The Employee Tracking CLI was created with Node.js and MySQL.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Barista**

(Starbucks Ottawa, ON Jan 2020 - Mar 2020)

- Served customers in a very fast-paced, high intensity work environment
- Acquired knowledge to provide outstanding customer service
- Developed teamwork collaboration and cooperation skills

#### **ESL Teacher**

(CL Education Center | Changwon, South Korea) (Nov 2018- Nov 2019)

- Taught English as a second language to kindergarten and elementary school students
- Developed curriculums and organized a variety of events for the children
- Gained confidence, enhanced interpersonal skills, while promoting self growth

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Trilogy's Coding Bootcamp**

(Feb 2020 - Present)

#### **Bachelor of Science**

University of Ottawa (Sep 2012 - Apr 2016)

- Full Stack Web Development
- A+ Average

Carleton University

- Specialization in Biochemistry
- \$2000 Entrance Scholarship